Maitri Shah

msparkle85@gmail.com 248.904.7038

SKILLS

USER-CENTERED DESIGN
TEAM LEADERSHIP AND DEVELOPMENT
CROSS-FUNCTIONAL RELATIONSHIPS
UX STRATEGY
CREATIVE DIRECTION
INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE
OPERATIONAL EFFECTIVENESS

OTHER EXPERIENCE

UX Mentor, Avocademy
UX Manager, Fuego UX
Technical Designer, Nike
Ouantitative Business Research Methods

Tutor, MSU Broad College of Business

CERTIFICATE

UX Strategy for Emerging Technologies, New York University

EDUCATION

MS, Information Technology, Digital Media and Instructional Design (partially complete), **Harvard University**

BS, Finance, **Michigan State University**BA, Apparel and Textile Design, **Michigan State University**

AAS, Fashion Design, **Fashion Institute of Technology**

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

WINNER, independent study program resulting in new accredited course offering in design curriculum, MSU

CAPTAIN, dance team, MSU

WINNER, merit-based full scholarship for 8 semesters, MSU

WINNER, Critic's Award for Sportswear Design, FIT

SUMMARY

A natural and experienced leader who brings ideas that challenge the status quo into coordinated team collaboration. Expert at producing clarity and establishing processes in areas of high ambiguity in various industries. Adept at facilitating reviews and providing constructive feedback. Award-winning creative who is committed to lifelong learning and guiding teams to success.

EXPERIENCE

John Deere | UX Lead, E-Commerce May 2023 - July 2024

Leadership in UX, product and engineering collaboration: spearheaded partnerships across UX, product and engineering teams, effectively leading and guiding a cross-functional staff of 150+.

Strategic enterprise capability enhancements: played a pivotal role in streamlining enterprise capabilities, facilitating a successful transition for dealers to shop.deere.com, and driving increased dealer utilization.

Revenue growth and customer experience improvement: planned and executed key enhancements to the end-to-end customer shopping experience, resulting in a \$2.1M revenue boost for shop.deere.com and a 2% increase in conversion rates. Achieved this through strategic initiatives, including increasing add-to-cart impressions and reducing cart abandonment as part of FY24 OKR goals.

Arthur J. Gallagher | Senior Manager, Global UX Design July 2021- March 2023

Global design leadership and team building: recruited and led a high-performing, multidisciplinary global design team, fostering innovation and collaboration across diverse functions.

Design system strategy and ownership: spearheaded the roadmap for building, scaling and maintaining design systems that drive workflow efficiency and ensure brand consistency across multiple brands.

Outfront Media | Interactive Design Manager, Product Experience July 2019 - July 2021

Creative and VR development leadership: led regular reviews and delivered impactful feedback to creative and virtual reality development teams, setting a high standard of quality for a VR preview tool designed for advertiser partners.

CX strategy and business growth: developed a customer experience (CX) strategy that played a critical role in securing two multimillion-dollar contracts for the department, driving significant business growth.

Havas | UX Consultant June 2019 - July 2019

Creative direction and brand identity leadership: directed creative efforts for a high-profile brand identity project, conducting critiques with designers and copywriters to ensure top-tier results.

Executive collaboration: collaborated directly with executive stakeholders, including the CEOs of Havas North America and Havas New York, regularly sharing progress and integrating their feedback to align the project with strategic goals.

Practicing Law Institute | Senior UI Designer

November 2015 - February 2019

Pioneering product design and team development: initiated the creation of the company's first product design role and earned two promotions during my tenure. Trained and developed a team of designers, while formally mentoring graphic designers to enhance the art department's skill set.

Cross-functional collaboration and innovation: partnered with UX, product management and engineering teams to deliver customer-facing digital products. Collaborated with UX to document and maintain a component library, ensuring design consistency.

Creative leadership and process improvement: created promotional artwork for multichannel campaigns, driving brand impact across platforms. Voluntarily conceptualized and implemented a streamlined request system to improve collaboration between marketing and art teams.

AIQ | Web Designer June 2013 - July 2015

Solo design leadership in a startup environment: took initiative to learn and deliver on all print and digital creative needs as the sole designer at a small startup, ensuring high-quality outputs across all channels.